

Principal Engineer seeking assignments in Software Development, Application Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Gap Analysis, SDLC, Python, Perl, C, Linux, DevOps Automation, Ansible, Shell Scripting



Current Designation: Principal Engineer -IT Total Experience: 12 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Company: Oracle Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Australia, Canada Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Principal Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Program

Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Gap Analysis, SDLC, Python, Perl, C, Linux, DevOps Automation, Ansible, Shell Scripting

Email - id Verified: Phone Number |

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

# Summary

Total Experience: 12.6 yrs into Python Programming, Perl, Shell , C , Linux , DevOps Automation. I am a competent and diligent IT professional, offering 12.6 years of experience in IT Industry including Software Engineering, Quality Management, DevOps and Project Management. I possess comprehensive knowledge of all phases of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) with a good understanding of System Study, Design, Client Interaction, Coordination, Development, and Implementation of Application Software. I am well versed in the end-to-end development of software products from requirement analysis to system study, designing, coding, testing, de-bugging, documentation & implementation.

Armed with strong techno-commercial acumen and significant devotion. I have been consistently exceeding performance benchmarks and steering my way forward towards resolving complex technical problems and meeting deadlines.

# Work Experience

Oracle as Principal Engineer -IT Sep 2018 to Till Date

Accountable for DevOPs Automation .

Currently Trained on Java script ,Oracle JET .

Working on Automation for Development Operations Requirements.

## Fidelity Information Services as Technical Lead

Nov 2016 to Sep 2018

Client Title- Senior Programmer Analyst

Description -

Accountable for requirements gathering from the client and preparing the requirement specifications documents of the module assigned.

Interact with the concerned teams for system study, requirements gathering, analysis and scoping; Identifying, analyze defects & in-consistencies in software program functions, outputs, online screens & content related to the DevOps project. Worked on Platform Configuration Audit -> My contribution towards Middleware Audit Automation ,RHEL and Oracle Platform Audit Auotmation .

Owned the Audit Self Heal Automation and successfully delivered and implemented it covering certain percent of Failures

hit regarding Self Heal contributing towards it.

Worked on Health Check Automation

Currently Working on Middleware Automation -> Successfully delivered 2 modules .

## HP R&D as Senior Software Engineer & Tech Lead Jul 2012 to May 2016

Accountable for requirements gathering from the client and preparing the requirement specifications documents of the module assigned.

Worked as Technical Lead in Recent Project in HP and Actively Managed a Team of 7 Developers

Interact with the users for system study, requirements gathering, analysis and scoping; Identifying, analyze defects & inconsistencies in software program functions, outputs, online screens & content related to the project.

Exposure in end-to-end development from requirement analysis to system study, designing, coding, testing and debugging Creating detailed design documents and unit test case documents of the module assigned.

Understanding & analysis of client requirement, designing concept document of requirement; handling unit testing and defect fixing

Provide direct support & development of the software applications/ tools, involving all phases of the software development life cycle (SDLC) for development functions related to large complex applications & software programs

Develop scripts for nightly build and fix defects for the Ignite deployment project using HPUX, PERL

Develop scripts for HPUX module "Virtprovider" using HPUX, PERL, client level commands

Develop the script for Directory Change notification (every file operation there is an inotify event). Develop the whole module using Perl Scripting

Modify the inotify API (Inotify API can be used to monitor individual files, or to monitor directories) binaries C files and integrating with Qarun script

Program for sequence file's operation and check return events

Program to check that inotify work for a directory

Modify the existing case insensitive scripts and fixed the code for the failures

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from DR. AMBEDKAR INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, BANGALORE in 2007

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version L	_ast Used	Experience
Perl, Python, DevOps			
Ansible, Unix, Linux, Kernel			
C, Java, Shell Scripting			

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
HINDI	Proficient			
Kannada	Proficient			

## **Affirmative Action**

**Work Authorization** 

Category: General

US Work Status: Authorized to Work in the US

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time